Uurtsaikh Nyambat

Senior Lead Software Developer

+976 8666 6217 • vvrtsaix.n@gmail.com • Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia

Profile

Experienced software developer skilled in system architecture, team leadership, development, testing, maintenance, integration, cloud platforms, and DevOps. Enthusiastic team player with strong software development expertise.

Certifications

CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator

Linux Foundation

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Amazon Web Services

Work Experience

Senior Lead Software Developer, Monosolution LLC

Feb 2023

- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious but realistic coding milestones for pre-release software project development.
- Collaborated on stages of the system development lifecycle, from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Developed software for web and mobile operating systems.
- Implemented a microservices architecture that improved system modularity and reduced dependencies between components
- · Conducted code reviews and mentored junior developers to improve code quality and ensure adherence to best practices

Chief Cloud Architect, FIBO GLOBAL LLC

Feb 2022 - Feb 2023

- Displayed a sound understanding of standard networking protocols, virtual networks, and load balancing.
- Identified and remedied single points of failure and security risks.
- Defined cloud architecture for both hybrid and non-hybrid cloud solutions.
- Interfaced directly with customers, stakeholders, and end-users regarding capability architectures, requirements, use cases, and stories to derive, develop, and decompose next-cycle updates and specifications.
- Worked with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability, and performance.
- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded performance expectations.

Senior Software Engineer, FIBO GLOBAL LLC

Jun 2021 - Feb 2022

- Coordinated efficient large-scale software deployments.
- Evaluated and improved the development work of other developers on the team, working to provide training, constructive criticism, and knowledge transfer.
- Evaluated project requirements and specifications and developed software applications that surpassed client expectations.
- Designed updates to existing software to meet changing customer demands.

Full Stack Engineer, Eclinic

Jul 2020 - Dec 2020

- Paired with fellow engineers to brainstorm ideas, debug problems, and review code.
- Performed development, debugging, optimization, and automation to support the implementation of products and applications.

Skills

Software development (5 years)

Team management (3 years)

Cloud Solutions Architect (3 years)

System Architecture (3 years)

DevOps (3 years)

Mobile Application Developer, Codocore

Jun 2020 - Jul 2020

• Maintained expansive knowledge of widely accepted design principles for developing applications within React Native environments.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Computer Software Engineering

2016 - 2020 - Mongolian University of Science and Technology

Languages

Mongolian - Native

English - Intermediate